Mike Trumbell

About

I'm a technologist from Chicago, IL with over 10 years of experience building web and mobile apps, REST APIs, and back office enterprise solutions. I bring a unique perspective to a development team and my diverse background allows me to solve a wide range of difficult problems through software.

Experience

Software Engineering Lead, Vela/OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2015-Present

- Led the successful migration from a legacy Windows application to an EmberJS multiplatform application (Electron). The project involved months of planning, leading a team of devs, replacing dozens of features to support hundreds of existing customers.
- Built a multi-device (Android and iOS) mobile application that reused many of our web components.
- Mentored 2 developers (EmberJS and Django) in building and maintaining 5 different production applications and assisted them with organizing quarterly goals.
- Managed weekly releases to our client applications including writing release notes and notifying high profile customers of large changes
- Built several API (Scala) features including a new permission framework which closely resembles the Django permissions model
- Successfully satisfied a CME market data entitlements audit by organizing years worth of subscription data from both the City and Metro platforms

Software Engineer, OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2011-2015

- Designed and implemented the internal support and CRM application that manages releases for all installations of the company's primary trading platform. (*Django and JavaScript*)
- Interviewed support staff to design features to quickly turn around requests.
- Designed and implemented an externally facing customer portal (Django/Javascript) to allow Risk Admins to manage trader risk limits.
- Designed and implemented a framework (Django/Celery) to allow support staff to easily configure complex customer reporting jobs interfacing with hundreds of software nodes and databases.

Software Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2009-2011

- Added features to Django/JavaScript application for administering (software updates, instance recycling, database migrations and reports, etc.) trading platforms.
- Streamlined commercial trader signup process to allow for quicker access to our trading platform.
- Administered all database migrations using Django/South and organized and scheduled them per trading exchange's maintenance windows.
- Built custom reports and tools for traders to manage their positions, load balance trading strategies per instance, separate network traffic for optimal performance and to help automate dozens of other day-to-day operations.

Application Support Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2008-2009

- Built and maintained hardware for low-latency, high-performance trading system.
- · Led classes at the CBOT about how to use our platform.
- Administered farm of servers and ensured application health through monitoring (Nagios, Hyperic, Smokeping, etc.).
- Fielded support calls from professional traders and answered questions on a wide range of topics including position information, order status, latency and computer performance.
- Wrote scripts (Python and Bash) to automate the management and debugging of our production applications.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

- JavaScript (EmberJS, JQuery)
- Python/Django
- · Scala/Play

Databases and Cloud

- SQL (MySQL, PostGreSQL)
- MongoDB
- · Google Firebase
- · AWS

Education

Central Michigan University - BS in Management Information Systems, 2006